Hello English learners,
welcome back to another
lesson here with us at
English pod, my name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we are going to have
a very casual, normal conversation.
That's right, we're
going to listen in on
some small talk between a
taxi driver and the passenger.
Small talk, so that's
basically small, short
conversations you have with
someone that you don't know very well.
Okay, so typical questions like how
old are you, where you're from, etc.
That's right.
And this can be
really hard for English
learners because they
often don't know what the
right thing to say or the
right thing to talk about.
So we're going to
give you a lot of phrases
in this lesson that you
can use in small talk.
Okay, so we don't have
anything to preview today.
So let's listen to the dialogue for
the first time and then we'll come back.
How are you doing Miss?
Hi, Crenshaw and Hawthorne, I
have a holiday in that is on that corner.
Sure thing, so where
are you flying in from?
From China.
Really?
You don't look very Chinese
to me, if you don't let me say so.
It's fine, I am actually from Mexico.
I was in China on a
business trip visiting
some local companies that
manufacture bathroom products.
Wow, sounds interesting, excuse me if
I'm being a bit nosy, but how old are you?
Don't you know it's rude
to ask the lady her age?
Don't get me wrong,
it's just that you seem
so young and are you
doing business overseas?
Well, thank you, in that case, I am
26 years old and what about yourself?
I am 40 years old and
was born and raised here
in the good old U.S. of A, although
I have some Colombian heritage.
Really?
That's great, do you speak Spanish?
Yeah, of course.
So I don't think this guy
spoke much Spanish, do you?
Even though he has Colombian
heritage, I think he doesn't speak much.
But maybe he's just a little bit rusty.
Maybe, but what he
does speak is English and
since this is English
pod, why don't we look
at some of the phrases that they
used for small talk and fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
All right, so today on
Fluency Builder, we're
going to take a look
at phrases that both
the passenger and the taxi
driver used to make small talk.
So why don't we start with the first one?
All right, so the
taxi driver tells the
passenger that she doesn't look very
Chinese if you don't mind me saying so.
Right, so he said, you don't look very
Chinese to me if you don't mind me saying so.
If you don't mind me saying so.
So what does he mean by
this last part of his sentence?
Well, this is a phrase
that we use to soften
a sort of statement that
might be a little bit rude.
She could be Chinese, right?
So it may be a little bit rude to
say that, but he kind of apologizes.
That's right.
By saying, if you don't mind me saying so.
Okay, so for example, I
could say, hey, Marco, you look
a little tired today if you
don't mind me saying so.
Okay, so does it always go at the end?
You could use it at the beginning.
If you don't mind me saying so, I
just don't think this is a good idea.
Okay, very good.
So you can use this phrase in the
beginning or at the end of a sentence.
Right, and it makes
your statement a little
bit less rude if you
don't mind me saying so.
Now again, he also apologizes a little bit
when he says, excuse me if I am being a bit
nosy, but excuse me if I'm being a bit
nosy, but excuse me if I'm being a bit nosy,
but okay, so let's
take a look at this nosy.
What's this?
Okay, when somebody is nosy,
it means they're very curious.
They are asking too many questions.
Yeah, asking more questions
than they should ask.
Right.
So he apologizes and says,
well, excuse me if I'm asking
too many questions, and then
he asks her another question.
He asks her how old she is.
Right.
So again, it's a polite
way of maybe asking a
question that might
be a little bit sensitive.
Yeah, or a little bit in polite.
Okay.
So of course, asking a woman her age,
maybe he's a little bit in polite, right?
Yes, typically women
don't like that too much.
But our next phrase, we heard the
taxi driver say, don't get me wrong.
Don't get me wrong.
Okay, so don't get me wrong.
He says, well, don't
misunderstand what I'm saying.
That's right.
This phrase is used so
commonly in English that
I think it would help us
to hear some examples.
Number one, don't get me wrong.
It's not that I think
you stole my computer.
It's just that you were the only
one who could get into my room.
Example two, I do have a few problems
with the plan, but don't get me wrong.
I still think it's a good idea.
Example three, I don't get me wrong.
I think John's a nice guy.
He's just a bit disorganized.
All right, very good example,
so don't get me wrong, right?
That's right.
And now for the final phrase
on putting it together today.
Well, the passenger,
the woman says her age
and she says, I'm 26 years
old and what about yourself?
What about yourself?
All right, now, this sentence
isn't very correct actually, right?
Yeah, technically it's
not correct in grammar,
but it is used so
commonly every day by
American English speakers that
we thought we'd show it to you.
Okay, so you would say, I am
26 years old and what about you?
That's right.
Okay, but commonly you will hear
people say, what about yourself?
And if you use this, you'll sound
really fluent and really native like.
Okay, very good.
So what about yourself?
So again, it's just like, what about you?
So I could say, hey,
Marko, I'm going away on
holiday this weekend
and what about yourself?
Okay, what about yourself?
So we've taken a look at these
four phrases on putting it together.
Why don't we listen to the
dialogue for the second time?
We're going to slow
it down a little bit and
then we'll come back and take a look at
some vocabulary words on language takeaway.
Hi, Crenshaw and Hawthorne at
the holiday inn that is on that corner.
Sure thing.
So where are you flying in from?
From China.
Really?
You don't look very Chinese to
me if you don't mind me saying so.
It's fine.
I am actually from Mexico.
I was in China on a
business trip, visiting some
local companies that
manufacture bathroom products.
Wow, sounds interesting.
Excuse me if I'm being a bit
nosy, but how old are you?
Don't you know it's
true to ask a lady her age.
Don't get me wrong.
It's just that you seem so young
and already doing business overseas.
Well, thank you.
In that case, I am 26 years
old and what about yourself?
I am 40 years old and
was born and raised here
in the good old U.S. of A, although
I have some Colombian heritage.
Really?
That's great.
Do you speak some Spanish?
Uh, yeah.
Of course.
Gebien!
And don't say "spo de
mo sub la de en espanol."
Well, we've got some
interesting vocabulary
words and phrases here
in language take away.
And the first one.
Well, after she gets
in the taxi and tells him
where she wants to go, he
answers by saying, Sure thing.
Sure thing.
If I say, yeah, sure thing,
what does that mean?
Well, let's listen to some
examples to help us understand.
Example 1.
Do you mind letting me 100 bucks?
Sure thing.
Example 2.
Could you please send me
the email by the end of the day?
Sure thing.
Example 3.
Do you mind letting me 100 bucks?
Sure thing.
Could you please send me
the email by the end of the day?
Sure thing.
Example 4.
Can you get some milk on the way home?
Sure thing.
I'm on my way now.
Okay.
So sure thing.
Basically, yeah.
No problem.
Or okay.
Or I'll do it.
I'll do it.
Yep.
It's fine.
So it's a very common way.
You will hear this a lot when somebody
agrees or says, yes, no problem.
Yeah.
And again, it will help you sound
really native like to use this phrase.
Well, the next one.
The taxi driver says, I
was born and raised here.
I was born and raised here.
Born and raised.
Okay.
So this is a way of
saying I was born in
this country and I
haven't left this country.
That's right.
So I'm from this country.
Okay.
Born and raised here
in the good old U.S.
of A, good old U.S. of
A, the good old U.S. of A.
So this is a pretty interesting
way of saying America.
Right.
It's actually more of a phrase, right?
The good old U.S. of A.
Yep.
So it means the good
United States of America.
Yeah.
It's kind of a fond way or
friendly way of describing America.
All right.
And we have one more
word for language takeaway.
Well, the taxi driver was talking
about his Colombian heritage.
Colombian heritage.
Heritage.
All right.
So if I have Colombian
heritage, what does that mean?
Your grandmother or,
you know, grandfather,
great grandmother or someone
in your family is from Colombia.
Okay.
What about the word heritage by itself?
Yeah.
So your heritage is basically your culture,
your customs, your customs, your history.
Okay.
So heritage, a country
rich in heritage, lots
of good old historical
culture in that country.
Okay.
Very good.
So now it's time for us to listen
to the dialogue for the last time.
Now we can understand
all these phrases and
these great words that
we've just looked at.
And then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
Where to miss?
Hi.
Crenshaw and Hawthorne at the
holiday inn that is on that corner.
Sure thing.
So where are you flying in from?
From China.
Really?
You don't look very Chinese to
me if you don't mind me saying so.
It's fine.
I am actually from Mexico.
I was in China on a
business trip visiting
some local companies that
manufacture bathroom products.
Wow.
Sounds interesting.
Excuse me if I'm being a
bit nosy but how old are you?
Don't you know it's rude
to ask the lady her age?
Don't get me wrong.
It's just that you seem so young
and already doing business overseas.
Well, thank you.
In that case, I am 26 years
old and what about yourself?
40 years old and was born
and raised here in the good
old U.S. of A. Although I
have some Colombian heritage.
Really?
That's great.
Do you speak Spanish?
Uh, yeah, of course.
(speaking Spanish)
So Marco, this taxi
driver makes a bit of a
mistake when he asks
the woman how old she is.
Yes.
Yeah, exactly.
There are a couple of questions that in
some cultures are considered to be normal in
okay, but in other cultures
they're not really well accepted.
Okay, so an Anglo
culture, for example, it's
really in polite to ask a
woman how old she is.
Right, women are a little bit
more sensitive about their age.
Others aren't so much but
it's usually better to just not ask.
Yep.
And what else should we
avoid talking about in small talk?
Well for example, when
you ask a person their
occupation, you can
ask what they do for
a living but don't ask how
much money they make.
That's right.
Anglo people are really sensitive
about talking about money.
We hate talking about money.
Right, so don't ask
somebody their salary or how
much money they make, it's
just not considered to be polite.
And another good one to be careful
of is asking if someone is married or not.
Right, sometimes
you're just being friendly
and you want to know
if that person has family
or something, but you have to be careful
when and where you ask this question.
Right, so if they've
mentioned their family,
if they've talked about
their kids or something
else to do with their
family, then it's okay.
Right, you can say, "Well, how
long have you been married?
" Yeah.
But if a guy asks a girl or you married, it
kind of sounds like maybe he's interested
in her or that he's
trying to come on to her
and to be maybe more
than friendly, right?
That's right.
Okay.
So some great small talk tips
and phrases here at EnglishPods.
Now if you have any
questions about this
lesson or any other lessons, be sure
to visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
And if you also have
any doubts about which
questions you think
are appropriate of asking
somebody, yeah, come into
the website and let us know.
So thanks for downloading, you guys.
And until next time, goodbye.